Matt Kocubinski

Software Developer and Engineer

Summary

Versatile programmer and systems administrator. Polyglot with experience in a variety of different languages, programming styles, problem domains, and systems.

Skills

Languages C/C++, C#, Java, Clojure, Lisp, Javascript, Coffescript, Python, Lua, F#, VB, PHP, HTML/CSS, Bash, Perl, Ruby, SQL, AHDL, MELFA Basic, Assembly.

Platforms &

.NET, JVM, GNU/Linux, Windows, HP MPE/iX, Node.js, Altera FPGAs,

Frameworks Clojurescript, Django, Drupal, Wordpress, Rails.

Tools/Libraries Emacs, Microsoft Visual Studio, Altera Quartus, Eclipse, Vim, JQuery, Twitter Bootstrap, NHibernate, WPF, Windows Forms, log4net, NUnit, MySQL, SQLite, Torque Game Engine, DirectX SDK, Apache, Nginx, Jetty, Postfix, ElasticSearch, Windows Driver Kit (WDK), Git, SVN.

Experience

2010-present **Software Developer**, *PharmaSeg*, *Inc.*, Princeton, NJ.

Develop and maintain key software programs for product development and research. Work closely with engineers and biologists to improve software, and develop to specifications. Projects:

- o "Tsunami" device control and data analysis. High speed data capture and analysis. Control of many different subsystems.
 - USB Driver development and debugging C/C++, WDK
 - Application development .NET, C#, F#, WPF, C++/CIL, Clojure, SQL
 - Embedded systems programming and control AHDL, C
- PharmaSeq "Wand" device control
 - Application development C#.NET, Windows Forms, DirectX SDK.
- Mitsubishi Industrial Pick and Place Robot Programming. Rapidly developed, compiling Clojure to MELFA Basic for a dynamic program.
 - Communications Layer RS-232 Serial Port, Clojure.
 - Application Layer .NET, Clojure, SQL.

2011-present **Programmer**, Legions: Overdrive, www.legionsoverdrive.com.

Member of a volunteer development team for the multiplayer game Legions: Overdrive.

- Modify and extend Torque Game Engine, in C/C++.
- Write Torquescript to add new features to game.
- Develop game launcher in C#.NET to sync client with deployed version on SVN. Maintain Django server to interface with launcher.
- Developing next-gen product in the Unity4 game engine (C#) with custom networking on top of Lidgren.

2009-present **Private Software Consultant**.

Web development for various clients.

- o Clojure/Clojurescript for rapid prototyping and a unified client/server language.
- HTML/CSS templating. JQuery for pretty and interactive pages.
- o Experience in PHP and popular CMS Wordpress, Drupal, Joomla.
- Linux webserver administration and maintenance.

2009–2010 **Engineer**, Packet Publications, Princeton, NJ.

Maintain LAN and WAN access for approximately 200 clients.

Maintain and develop servers for mail, data storage, publishing workflow, billing/account routines, backups.

Systems used:

- Linux/Unix/Windows servers
- High-availability server clusters
- o DNS/BIND, NFS, LDAP, Samba, AD
- Cisco IOS routing and firewalls
- o Perl, Bash, VBScript, Expect
- SQL, IBM Informix DBs

Education

2003–2006 **Associates of Music**, *Mercer County Community College*, Hamilton, NJ, *GPA 3.7*. Study of Jazz Performance on Drumset, Music Theory/History, Calculus 1-3.

2007–2008 **Electrical Engineering**, *Rutgers University*, New Brunswick, NJ, *GPA 3.8*. Fundamentals of Electrical Engineering, AC/DC, RLC Circuits, Filter Design, Digital Logic Design.

Interests/Hobbies

Staying in shape - weight lifting, running, soccer, skiing, Tai'Chi. Practicing and performing music.